[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这是最简单的XSS攻击，并且
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: This is the simplest XSS attack, and
只是为了向你展示野兽的真实面貌。
just to show you what the beast actually looks like.
所以在这次袭击中
So, in this attack,
攻击者欺骗您的用户点击一个看起来像这样的URL。
the attacker tricks your user into clicking on a URL that looks like that.
这是一个看起来很奇怪的URL，里面有尖括号和疯狂的东西，而且
It's a really weird looking URL with angle brackets and crazy stuff in it, and
你可能会想，没有用户会点击它，不幸的是，他们不会。
you might think, no user would ever click on that, and unfortunately, no, they will.
而且，如果他们足够聪明，不会点击看起来像这样的URL，
And, if they're smart enough not to click on a URL that looks like that,
他们可能会点击bit.ly URL。
they'll probably click on a bit.ly URL.
它可能会接受二维码，所以是的，他们会去那里。
It'll probably accept a QR code, so yeah, they're gonna go there.
因此，过去Web服务器在默认情况下只需执行以下操作
And so, it used to be that Web servers, by default, would simply take
文件名，并将其粘贴在404页的正文中，然后将其发送回。
the file name and stick it in the body of a 404 Page and send it back.
在这种情况下，现在HTML上下文中，它变成了一个脚本标记，
In this case, now in the HTML context, that becomes a script tag,
然后执行来自世界上最危险的服务器的加载脚本。
which will then execute a load script from the world's most dangerous server.
他们可以访问你在浏览器上得到的一切。
They get access to everything that you've got on the browser.
他们有你的饼干，他们有你的本地仓库，
They've got your cookies, they've got your local storage,
他们让Chrome说这是一个有效的东西。
they've got the Chrome saying this is a valid thing.
所以，当他们问你密码的时候，一切都很好，而且
So, when they ask for your password, everything's good, and
关于这一点有数千种，也许数百万种变体，而且
there are thousands, maybe millions, of variations on this, and
安全专家可以通过发现另一个主题来获得一些主题。
a security expert can get some theme by discovering another one.
他们总是可以这样做，因为这些东西的供应是无穷无尽的，但是
They can always do that because there is an endless supply of these things, but
所有这些问题的解决方案都是完全相同的。
the solution to all of these is exactly the same.
所有的东西都必须被正确过滤，所有的东西都必须被正确地编码。
Everything has to be filtered correctly, everything has to be encoded correctly.
所以，如果你对这个进行编码，并在放上它之前把它们变成实体，
So, if you encode this and turn those into entities before putting it on,
然后它就会变得惰性，在任何地方都这样做就变得非常重要了。
then it becomes inert, and it becomes really important to do that everywhere.
如果你在任何地方都能正确地做到这一点，
If you do that correctly everywhere,
那么这种注入攻击就不可能发生了。
then these sorts of injection attacks cannot happen.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的，我想我错过了第一部分，所以
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: All right, okay, I think I'm missing the first part of this, so
你去yoursite.com，所有这些胡说八道，这个脚本都在里面。
you go to yoursite.com, all this nonsense, this script that's in there.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：服务器以404作为响应，但它会将该内容粘贴在其中吗？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And the server responds with 404, but it sticks that content in it?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，它接受文件名，放入，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, it takes the filename, puts it in,
说这是我们找不到的文件。
says this is the file we couldn't find.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：我明白了，所以好吧，现在这个脚本运行一个表单，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: I see, so okay, and now this script runs a form that says,
请提交您的密码，他们会将密码发送给您。
please submit your password, and they send it their password, whatever.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yep.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：不管是什么。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Whatever it is.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：不管它是什么。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Whatever it is.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：事实上，这个脚本现在可以与双方对话。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: In fact, this script can now talk to both sides.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yep.
&gt；&gt；演讲者3：你是说缓解是在404页你完成的
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: And you're saying the mitigation is done in the 404 Page you
在你的服务器上。
have on your server.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对，所以实际上，服务器可以构建的每个页面
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right, so in fact, every page your server can construct
需要为所有输入的所有情况正确地进行此编码。
needs to do this coding correctly for all cases for all inputs.
&GT；&GT；演讲者2：你永远不应该告诉他们提交了什么，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: You should never tell them what they submitted,
它应该只是说没有找到那个页面。
it should just say that page isn't found.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：对，就像另一个例子一样，这是一个没有
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Right, like another example, this is one that doesn't
需要在雅虎上的第二个网站。
require a second site on Yahoo.
他们以前有个人资料页面，在你的个人资料页面上，
They used to have profile pages, and on your profile page,
有一个性别的盒子。
there's a box for gender.
作为非常好的人，他们允许你在盒子里输入任何你想要的东西，
Being very nice people, they allowed you to type anything you wanted into that box,
所以你不需要选择M或F
so it wasn't like you have to pick M or F.
他们说，不管你想要什么，都可以。
They said, whatever you want, that's okay.
有很多人都想通了，它是从一个尖括号开始的，
There were a lot of people who figured out, it starts with an angle bracket,
然后在那里输入一个脚本标签。
and it's, type a script tag in there.
所以，这意味着每次有人看你的个人资料页面，
And so, it means every time anybody looked at your profile page,
他们可以窃取你的帐户。
they can steal your account.
MySpace也发生了类似的事情。
There was a similar thing that happened in MySpace.
有个叫萨米的人发现了MySpace
There was a guy named Sammy who figured out MySpace,
在那个时候，有点聪明，并且有一些过滤器。
at that time, was a little bit smarter and had some filters.
但是，这个叫萨米的家伙找到了绕过他们的方法，然后
But, this guy named Sammy figured out how to get around them, and
所以他注入了一个脚本，每当有人查看他的个人资料页面时，
so he injected a script that, whenever anybody looked at his profile page,
脚本将运行，然后将他添加到他们的英雄列表中。
the script would run and then add him to their Heroes list.
哪一个是好友列表中最好的位置，并将该脚本放到他们的
Which is the best spot on the friends list and put that script onto their
页面也是如此，所以看过其中一个页面的人的数量也是如此
page as well, and so the number of people who had looked at one of
这些页面每分钟翻一番，或者，不，每小时左右翻一番。
these pages doubled every minute, or, no, every hour or so.
在20小时内，他控制了200万个账户
In 20 hours, he had control of two million accounts and
大约在那个时候，MySpace说，哇，发生什么事了？
about that time MySpace went, whoa, what's going on?
他们关闭了它，但你仍然可以在网上搜索
And they shut it down, but you can still search out on the Web for
Sammy是我的英雄，你可能还会在外面找到一些这样的东西。
Sammy Is My Hero, and you'll probably still find some of these out there.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这是这次攻击的一个版本，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So that's a version of this attack,
萨米原来是个好人。
and Sammy turns out to be a nice guy.
我不知道他是不是个好人，但他认出了，哎哟，
I don't know if he's a nice guy, but he recognized, whoops,
我没想到我会在一天内接手太多客户，
I didn't expect I'd take over too many accounts in a day,
所以他会自首并被指控犯罪。
so he'd turn himself in and was charged with a crime.
&GT；&GT；演讲者2：可能在白宫某处找到一份甜蜜的工作。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Probably got a sweet job working in the somewhere White House.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：是的，我肯定萨米，我想他做得还不错。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, I'm sure Sammy, I assume he did okay.
他可能是个坏人，对吧？
He could have been a bad guy, right?
他本可以自己留着
He could have just kept it to himself and
找到了如何利用这两百万人。
figured out how to exploit these two million people.
您还需要担心连接，所以
You also need to worry about concatenation, so
JavaScript中的加号运算符是危险的。
the plus sign operator in JavaScript is dangerous.
这取决于你如何使用它，因为你可以取一些字符串和
Depending on how you're using it, because you can be taking bits of string and
把它们放在一起，在某些情况下，如果你只是把文本放在一起，
putting them together, and in some cases, if you're just putting together text,
这不是问题。
it's not a problem.
但是，如果您正在做一些类似于组装JSON或
But, if you're doing something like assembling JSON or
组装HTML，有可能变坏。
assembling HTML, there is a potential for that to go bad.
所以，只要有可能，你应该使用好的编码器和
So, whenever possible, you should be using good encoders and
作家，而不是仅仅试图把东西加在一起。
writers and not just trying to plus things together.
所以，我很高兴地报告，这显然不再是
So, I'm very happy to report that this is no longer apparently
不安全感的来源。
a source of insecurity.
一位经理，当被警告我们需要防范这一点时会问，
A manager, when being warned that we need to protect against this would ask,
为什么会有人这么做？
why would anybody do that?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：否。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我们现在知道
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: We now know
他为什么要这么做。
why he'll do that.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：我们仍然听到这个。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: We still hear that.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：真的吗？
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Do you really?
[相声]嗯，这是个问题。
[CROSSTALK] Well, that's a problem.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：是的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的，我们现在知道他们为什么会这么做了，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah, we now know why they will do that,
他们会这样做，因为我们可以阻止他们这样做。
they will do that because we can prevent them from doing that.
在某些公司的情况下，这些公司会无意中
In the case of some companies, those companies will unintentionally
付钱让他们这样做，在某些情况下，也许付给他们很好的报酬去做那件事。
pay them to do that, in some cases, maybe pay them really well to do that.
这些东西不是安全的，
These are things which are not security,
有时被认为是安全的。
which are sometimes thought of as being security.
例如，不便，我们不能阻止他们，但我们可以减缓他们。
For example, inconvenience, we can't stop them, but we can slow them down.
它将在信息高速公路上设置减速带，从而阻止它们。
It will put speed bumps on the information superhighway where will stop them.
那是行不通的，那些东西往往会给你带来比它们更多的不便。
That doesn't work, those things tend to inconvenience you more than them.
只是，再一次，如果没有效果，
It's just, again, if it's not effective,
这不是有效的，不要在上面浪费时间。
it's not effective and don't waste time on it.
身份不是安全。
Identity is not security.
找出某人是谁并不能回答这个问题，
Finding out who someone is doesn't answer the question of,
应该允许他们对你做什么？
what should they be allowed to do to you?
污染有时被认为是一种不起作用的安全模式。
Tainting is sometimes cited as a model of security that doesn't work.
这是一个你试图追踪数据来源的模型
It's a model where you try to track the source of data and
随着时间的推移，它是如何转变的，以及
how it's transformed over time, and
尝试确定在什么时候它会被污染或损坏，但它不起作用。
try to determine at what point it becomes tainted or corrupted, but it doesn't work.
最后，入侵检测不是安全的。
And then, finally, intrusion detection is not security.
有些系统管理员已经厌倦了被黑客攻击，
There are some system administrators who are so tired of being hacked,
他们已经放弃了阻止它的所有希望。
and they've given up all hope of stopping it.
他们只想知道什么时候发生，但这不是安全问题。
They just want to know when it's happening, but that's that's not security.
最大的可避免的安全来源，我们将在这里结束，是管理不善。
The biggest avoidable source of security, and we'll end here, is mismanagement.
当经理说，
It's when a manager says,
我们会通过保安人员的，因为我们有最后期限。
we're going to get this past the security guys because we've got a deadline.
我们必须面对它，我们必须走出去。
We've got to meet it, we've got to get out there.
我在电话线上得到了奖金。
I got a bonus on the line.
我们要走了，不要让它发生，你要踢它，因为没有
We're going to go, don't let that happen, you gotta kick it up cuz no
公司可以负担得起这样的事情在他们的网站上进行，因为
company can afford to have this kind of stuff going on in their sites, for
任何可能的短期收益。
any possible short-term gain.